Elier Hernandez

2+ years of experience

Website: https://elierhernandez.com

Email: elierporto@gmail.com

Address: 19322 NW 47TH PL, Miami Gardens, FL - 33055

Phone: (786) 478 - 5402

Miami-based Full Stack Web Developer with experience in all stages of development. Knowledgeable in testing, frameworks, debugging, agile principles and TDD. Proficient in an assortment of technologies, including Javascript, React, Nextjs, Sass, Ruby, Ruby on Rails and Postgresql. Able to self manage independent projects and collaborate in a team setting.

Skills

Html5, Css3, Sass, Javascript Es6+, React, Next.js, Typescript, Node.js, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, MongoDB, PostgreSQL

Experience

Freelance Web Developer

October 2021 - Present

In charge of web projects from concept to launch. Obtained a strong grasp of client relations, understanding client requirements, and turning those requirements into real world applications.

- Developed web applications with HTML, CSS, Javascript, React and Ruby on Rails.
- Provided a CMS for clients to facilitate website maintenance.
- Helped clients host their web apps and ensured that it stays live on the web.
- Built web mockups and wireframes using Figma as a design tool.

Skyline Media Marketing

Web Developer March 2018 - April 2020

Responsible for the development and operation of both in-house and customer-facing web applications. Worked as a team with other developers and designers to ensure the best results for our clients.

Skyline is an agency that works with multiple clients that all have different requirements. It was necessary for me to be highly adaptable and always willing to learn new technologies.

- Built client websites using HTML, CSS, Javascript, React, Gatsby and at times Wordpress.
- Helped agency clients build a strong online web presence.
- Ensured web pages are SEO compliant and allow for proper ranking.
- Built internal tools to improve company efficiency by more than 70%.

Projects

Pencils & Inks

E-commerce website developed from scratch using React & Next js for the client side and Ruby on Rails for the server APIs. The website includes various features such as; products, users, filter settings, a review system with ratings, a shopping cart, and an admin panel for CRUD operations.

React, Ruby on Rails

Webmarks

Online file system that allows users to store folders and urls on the web. The front end for this application was built using React and Material UI. The back end API was built using Node with Express, and the user authentication was handled with Passport.

React, Gatsby, Node

Skyline Media Marketing

Skyline is an advertisement agency located in New York. I worked with them for 2 years and developed their main website using React and Gatsby. After the creation of the website, the company experienced a 100%+ increase in leads from their marketing campaigns. It was a huge success.

React, Gatsby

Education

Miami Dade College

2011 - 2013

Pursued bachelors of computer science. Took essential college classes such as; Literature, Writing, Mathematics, Science, Humanities and Public Speaking.

Full Stack Web Developer Bootcamp

2019 - 2020

Took a web development bootcamp that taught me key development concepts and multiple programming skills, including; html, css, javascript and node js.

Modern React Bootcamp

2020 - 2021

Further expanded my skill-set by taking a React specific boot camp. This improved my react skills significantly. I learned about React classes, hooks, components, state management, api requests and life cycle methods.